Herbert Waide Hemphill
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Personal Business Records, 1817-1997, Series 3:; (Box 5-7, 28; 2.0 linear feet)
  - Grant Proposal for Film Collector/Collected, 1978-1979, (3 folders) (Box 5, Folder 51-53)
  - Grant Proposal for Traveling Exhibition by St. Lawrence City History Association, 1979, (2 folders) (Box 5, Folder 54-55)
  - Proposal for Exhibition "Lo! Behold! Visionary Folk Art of the Eighties," 1988 (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - Loan Agreements, undated (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - Loan Agreements, 1964-1974 (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - Loan Agreements, 1975, (4 folders) (Box 5, Folder 59-62)
  - Loan Agreements, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 63)
  - Loan Agreements, 1977, (4 folders) (Box 5, Folder 64-67)
  - Loan Agreements, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 68)
  - Loan Agreements, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 69)
  - Loan Agreements, 1980, (3 folders) (Box 5, Folder 70-72)
  - Loan Agreements, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Loan Agreements, 1982-1984 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Loan Agreements, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Loan Agreements, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Loan Agreements, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Loan Agreements, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Loan Agreements, 1990-1996 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous Deeds of Gift, 1976-1996, undated, (3 folders) (Box 6, Folder 8-10)
  - Bill of Sale/Accession Form for Hemphill Collection from International Folk Art Foundation of Santa Fe, New Mexico, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Accession Form for Hemphill Collection from National Museum of American Art, Smithsonian Institution, 1986-1987 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Art Work Appraisal Reports, 1961-1990, undated, (6 folders) (Box 6, Folder 13-18)
  - Price Lists for Art Work, 1993-1995, undated (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Photographs of Miscellaneous Art Work Marked with Prices, 1973-1995, undated, (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 20-21)
  - Consignment Records, 1969-1996, undated, (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 22-23)
  - Miscellaneous Honoraria, 1975-1985, undated (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Records of Royalties, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Income Tax Returns and Records, 1956-1989, (6 folders) (Box 6, Folder 26-31)
  - Occupancy Tax Records, 1974-1979 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Miscellaneous Banking Records, 1966-1991, undated, (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 33-34)
  - Cancelled Checks, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Cancelled Checks, 1963, (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 36-37)
  - Cancelled Checks, 1964, (4 folders) (Box 6, Folder 38-41)
  - Cancelled Checks, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Cancelled Checks, 1966, (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 43-44)
  - Cancelled Checks, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Cancelled Checks, 1968, (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 46-47)
  - Cancelled Checks, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Cancelled Checks, 1970, (4 folders) (Box 6, Folder 49-52)
  - Cancelled Checks, 1971, (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 53-54)
  - Cancelled Checks, 1972, (4 folders) (Box 6, Folder 55-58)
  - Cancelled Checks, 1973, (4 folders) (Box 6, Folder 59-62)
  - Cancelled Checks, 1974, (4 folders) (Box 6, Folder 63-66)
  - Cancelled Checks, 1975, (3 folders) (Box 6, Folder 67-69)
  - Cancelled Checks, 1976, (2 folders) (Box 7, Folder 1-2)
  - Cancelled Checks, 1977-1978 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Cancelled Checks, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Cancelled Checks, 1980, (3 folders) (Box 7, Folder 5-7)
  - Cancelled Checks, 1981, (2 folders) (Box 7, Folder 8-9)
  - Cancelled Checks, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Cancelled Checks, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Cancelled Checks, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Cancelled Checks, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Cancelled Checks, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Receipts for Purchase of Art Work, 1954-1997, undated, (15 folders) (Box 7, Folder 15-29)
  - Receipts for Conservation and Framing, 1968-1993, undated, (2 folders) (Box 7, Folder 30-31)
  - Receipts for Photographic Work and Supplies, 1972-1984, undated (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Receipts for Shipping and Storage, 1973-1994, undated (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Miscellaneous Travel Receipts, 1970-1997, undated, (5 folders) (Box 7, Folder 34-38)
  - Miscellaneous Receipts, 1958-1997, undated, (2 folders) (Box 7, Folder 39-40)
  - Oversized Indenture Document between Jane Vernon and Joseph Gibbons, 1817, (from Box 5, Folder 28) (Box 28)
- Artwork, 1911-1997, Series 4:; (Box 7, 32; 0.4 linear feet)
  Art work consists of a sketchbook by Roy Little, a set of hand-cut Japanese mask designs, a collage of Polaroid photographs created by Rev. Howard Finster, a hand-made book by Nancy Josephson, and miscellaneous drawings, watercolors, and prints by various artists including Justin McCarthy, Inez Nathaniel, and Nellie Mae Rowe.
  - Art Work for Hemphill's Business Card, undated (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - Drawing for Hemphill Catalog by Unidentified Artist, undated (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - Drawing of Hemphill Signed "Picasso II," undated (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - Drawings by Unidentified Artists, undated, (2 folders) (Box 7, Folder 44-45)
  - Fragment of a Watercolor by Unidentified Artist, undated (Box 7, Folder 46)
  - Block Prints by Unidentified Artists, undated (Box 7, Folder 47)
  - Japanese Cut-Out Faces, undated, (6 folders) (Box 7, Folder 48-53)
  - Collage by Rev. Howard Finster and Drawing by L. Hall, undated, (Oversized material housed in OV 32) (Box 7, Folder 54)
  - Drawing by Michael D. Hall, undated (Box 7, Folder 55)
  - Drawings by Justin McCarthy, undated (Box 7, Folder 56)
  - Etching by Henry W. Mitchell, undated (Box 7, Folder 57)
  - Drawing by Inez Nathaniel, undated (Box 7, Folder 58)
  - Drawing by Nellie Mae Rowe, undated (Box 7, Folder 59)
  - Etching by Robert Confils, 1911 (Box 7, Folder 60)
  - Drawing of Prof. Harry Clemons by Unidentified Artist, 1947 (Box 7, Folder 61)
  - Watercolor Drawing Signed "M. F. E.," 1949 (Box 7, Folder 62)
  - Sketchbook by Roy Little, 1951 (Box 7, Folder 63)
  - Drawing Signed "Roy," 1957 (Box 7, Folder 64)
  - Drawing Signed "Marco," 1960 (Box 7, Folder 65)
  - Drawings by Conrad LaFrance, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 66)
  - Drawing by Harold William Crowell, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 67)
  - Hand-Made Book The Court of the Seven Sisters by Nancy Josephson, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 68)
  - Oversized Collage by Rev. Howard Finster, undated, (from Box 7, Folder 54) (Box OV 32)
- Notes and Writings, 1938-1996, Series 5:; (Box 7-10, 28; 2.5 linear feet)
  Notes and writings include a card files of artists and notes on many folk artists including Miles Carpenter, Raymond Coins, Rev. Howard Finster, Mattie Lou O'Kelley, Royal Robertson, Veronica Terrillion, Mose Tolliver, and Bill Traylor. Also found are lists of artists, patrons, and art work, miscellaneous notes, minutes of meetings, reports and numerous typescript essays on art, folk art, and cultural history written by Hemphill and others including Michael D. Hall, Lynda Roscoe Hartigan, A. Everett James, and Julia Weissman.
  - Card File of Artists, undated, (2 folders) (Box 7, Folder 69-70)
  - Notes on Unidentified Artists, undated (Box 7, Folder 71)
  - Notes, George Aghassian, 1986, undated (Box 7, Folder 72)
  - Notes, Leroy Almon; David Michael Ambrose; Louis Bertrand, 1993, undated (Box 7, Folder 73)
  - Notes, M. S. Brown; Bert Bucklin; David Butler, undated (Box 7, Folder 74)
  - Notes, Miles Carpenter, 1981-1984, undated (Box 7, Folder 75)
  - Notes, Raymond Coins; Jane Hancock Cummings; Dr. Thomas Davis, undated (Box 7, Folder 76)
  - Notes, Marguerite Doernbach; Sam Doyle; William Edmondson, 1993, undated (Box 7, Folder 77)
  - Notes, John Ehn, 1983-1986, undated (Box 7, Folder 78)
  - Notes, Rev. Howard Finster, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 79)
  - Notes, John Folinsbee, Anthony Frudakis, Romano Gabriel, Adelaide Lawson Gaylor, undated (Box 7, Folder 80)
  - Notes, Gary Giberson; Paul Glassman; Esther Hamerman, undated (Box 7, Folder 81)
  - Notes, James Hampton; John Harrison, undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Notes, Rick Hearn; Marilyn Keating, 1992, undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Notes, Simon Klippenstein; Gustav Klumpp, undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Notes, Nancy Berger Kraemer; Pierre Joseph Landry; J. L. M.; Eluid L. Martinez, 1994-1995, undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Notes, Nathaniel Mayhew; Edgar Alexander McKillop; Miller and Bryant, 1989, undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Notes, J. B. Murry; Tom Neugebauer, undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Notes, James Henry Norman, undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Notes, Mattie Lou O'Kelley, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Notes, John Peernock, 1991-1993, undated, (3 folders) (Box 8, Folder 9-11)
  - Notes, Guido Polo; Lamont Pry; Matteo Radoslovich, undated (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Notes, Royal Robertson; Joseph Sleep; Stark, undated (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Notes, Michael Suter; Rev. Johnnie S. Swearingen; Veronica Terrillion; Mose Tolliver, 1996, undated (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Notes, Bill Traylor; C. Wilhelm; Ben Wilson; Anton Zelenich, 1997, undated (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Lists of Artists and Patrons, 1962-1996, undated, (2 folders) (Box 8, Folder 16-17)
  - Lists of Names Connected with Folk Art and the Smithsonian Institution, 1988, undated, (2 folders) (Box 8, Folder 18-19)
  - Master Folk Art List, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Lists of Art Work, undated (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Notes on Individual Art Works, undated, (6 folders; Oversized material also housed in Box 28) (Box 8, Folder 22-27)
  - Caption Cards for Art Work, 1966-1987, undated (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Miscellaneous Lecture Notes, undated (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Notes from Seminar on Patroon Paintings, undated (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Notes on Folk Art Expedition Deck of Computer Cards, undated (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Science Class Notes with Drawings by Hemphill, 1945, (4 folders) (Box 8, Folder 32-35)
  - Director's Annual Report for Museum of American Folk Art, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - Report from Advisory Board Meeting of Community Environments, Inc., 1978 (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Notes from Board of Director's Meeting at Community Environments, Inc., 1979 (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - Library of Congress Folk Archive Reference Aid, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - Minutes of Meetings at Museum of American Folk Art, 1988-1996, (2 folders) (Box 8, Folder 40-41)
  - Notes from Symposium "Cult, Culture, and Consumers: Collecting the Work of Self-Taught Artists in Twentieth-Century America," 1991 (Box 8, Folder 42)
  - Bibliography Card File 1, undated (Box 8, Folder 43)
  - Bibliography Card File 2, undated (Box 8, Folder 44)
  - Draft Bibliography, 1996, (4 folders) (Box 9, Folder 1-4)
  - Hemphill Bibliography, 1996, (4 folders) (Box 9, Folder 5-8)
  - Miscellaneous Bibliographies, 1986, undated (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Report on Long Range Plan for Noyes Museum, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Notes from Seventh Annual New York State Folk Arts Roundtable, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Notes from Board/Staff Retreat of Museum of American Folk Art, 1992, (6 folders) (Box 9, Folder 12-17)
  - Notes Concerning Long-Range Plan of Museum of American Folk Art, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Report on Accomplishments of Development Department of Museum of American Folk Art, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Notes from Board Meeting and Retreat of Museum of American Folk Art, 1994, (3 folders) (Box 9, Folder 20-22)
  - Miscellaneous Addresses, undated (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Medical Notes, undated (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Miscellaneous Notes on the Theater, undated (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Miscellaneous Notes: Notebooks, undated (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, 1969-1973, undated, (3 folders) (Box 9, Folder 27-29)
  - Typescript on Origins of Naïve Painters by Hemphill, undated (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Manuscript "Art of the People, for the People, by the People," by Hemphill, undated (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Manuscript on Traditional and Non-Traditional Folk Art, by Hemphill, undated (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Manuscript on Various Folk Artists, by Hemphill, undated (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Typescript "Prospectus for a Book on Folk Art of the American Presidency," by Hemphill, undated (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Manuscript on the Desire to Collect, by Hemphill, undated (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Typescript "How to Buy folk Art," by Hemphill, undated (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Hand-Written Answers to a History Exam, by Hemphill, 1947 (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - Typescript "The Artist Self-Taught," by Hemphill, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - Typescript "Definition of Occult," by Hemphill and Julia Weissman, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - Typescript "Twentieth Century American Folk Art and Artists," by Hemphill and Julia Weissman, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 40)
  - Typescript "Commentary on Georgia folk Art," by Hemphill, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 41)
  - Miscellaneous Writings by Hemphill, undated, (2 folders) (Box 9, Folder 42-43)
  - Typescript "Art and Psychopathology," by Unidentified Author, undated (Box 9, Folder 44)
  - Typescript on Artists James and John Bard, by Unidentified Author, undated (Box 9, Folder 45)
  - Typescript for Exhibition Getting Dressed: Fashionable Appearance, 1750-1800 at National Museum of American History, Smithsonian Institution, by Unidentified Author, undated (Box 9, Folder 46)
  - Typescript "Ted Gordon," by Unidentified Author, undated (Box 9, Folder 47)
  - Typescript "Michael Hall: Construction, Not Constructivism," by Unidentified Author, undated (Box 9, Folder 48)
  - Typescript "History of the National Museum of American Art," by Unidentified Author, undated (Box 9, Folder 49)
  - Typescript "Ed Martin" (St. EOM), by Unidentified Author, undated (Box 9, Folder 50)
  - Typescript "On Collecting Art and Culture," by Unidentified Author, undated (Box 9, Folder 51)
  - Typescript for Exhibition Outsider Art, by Unidentified Author, undated (Box 9, Folder 52)
  - Typescript on Lamont Alfred Pry, by Unidentified Author, undated (Box 9, Folder 53)
  - Transcript of Speeches from an Award Ceremony for Malcah Zeldis, undated (Box 9, Folder 54)
  - Typescript "The Folk Pottery of Georgia," by Dr. John A. Burrison, undated (Box 9, Folder 55)
  - Typescript "The Twenty-One Rats of the Apocalypse," by Robert D. Franklin, undated (Box 9, Folder 56)
  - Typescripts on African Art, by A. Everette James, Jr., undated (Box 9, Folder 57)
  - Typescript "A Comment upon the Linguistic Analysis of Folk Art," by A. Everette James, Jr., undated (Box 9, Folder 58)
  - Typescript "Update, Status of?" by A. Everette James, Jr., undated (Box 9, Folder 59)
  - Typescript "Directory of Contemporary Folk Artists" by Andy Nasisse and Miriam Staples, undated (Box 9, Folder 60)
  - Typescript of Lectures by Jules D. Prown, undated (Box 9, Folder 61)
  - Typescript "New Mexican Santos: The Folk Art of Faith," by Julia Weissman, undated (Box 9, Folder 62)
  - Typescript of Lecture Notes "Prehistoric Caves, Medieval Castles and Renaissance Cathedrals" by Ian Tattersall, Helen Evans, and David Soren, undated (Box 9, Folder 63)
  - Typescript "Descansos" by Loren W. Brown, 1938 (Box 9, Folder 64)
  - Photocopy of Notes from Lecture "Anticultural Positions" by Jean Dubuffet, 1951 (Box 9, Folder 65)
  - Definitions of Folk Art Written by Students, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 66)
  - "Report: The Buck Farm by F. H. Sweet," by Frank McKelvey, Jr., 1968 (Box 9, Folder 67)
  - Thesis "Deborah Goldsmith, 1808-1836, a Naïve Artist in Upstate New York," by Sandra O. Shaffer, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 68)
  - Typescript of Text for Exhibition What is Folk Art? by Yvonne Lange, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 69)
  - Pages from Journal Recording Travel in the United States Written by an Unidentified Friend of Hemphill, 1974-1975 (Box 9, Folder 70)
  - Poems by John Freimarck, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 71)
  - Proposal for Guggenheim Fellowship by Nancy Flaun Kazlins, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 72)
  - Typescript "Expanding Frontiers: An Analysis of the Michigan Folk Art Project," by Marsha MacDowell and C. Kurt Dewhurst, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 73)
  - Typescript "A Guide to Holdings of the Traditional Craft Archive," by Mark H. Howard, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 74)
  - Typescript Draft: " Folk Art U.S.A. Since 1900," by Unidentified Author, 1980, (2 folders) (Box 9, Folder 75-76)
  - Typescript "A Man to Remember: Leonard L. 'Stoney' St. Clair," by Alan Govenar, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 77)
  - Typescript "The Museum of American Folk Art: A Social History," by Jeanne Bornstein, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 78)
  - Typescript of Introductory Remarks by Alan Jabbour at Washington Meeting on Folk Art, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 79)
  - Photocopy of Preface of Eye to Eye: Twenty years of Art Criticism by Robert Pincus-Witten, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 80)
  - Typescript Description of Travel Experiences Connected with Exhibition In Another World by Unidentified Author, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 81)
  - Typescript "In Africa: A Personal Journal," by William A. Fagaly, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 82)
  - Typescripts "What is Outsider Art?;" "Jon Serl: Master Outsider;" "Bessie Harvey: One Person Exhibit," 1987 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Typescript "A Heart for the Tin Man - This Side of Oz," by Michael D. Hall, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Typescript of Lecture Delivered by Robin Pearse for John August Swanson Exhibition, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Draft Report on Contemporary New York State Folk Art Exhibition, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Museum of American Folk Art Director's Report by Robert Bishop, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Typescript "Tapping at Art's Door" by Lynda Roscoe Hartigan, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Checklist for Exhibition Folk Art Across America by Lynda Roscoe Hartigan, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Typescript "Gumbo, Ya/Ya and Hey Pocky Way: African Americans Making New Orleans What It Is," by William A. Fagaly, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Typescript "The James Collection of Southern Folk Art," 1993, (3 folders) (Box 10, Folder 9-11)
  - Typescript "Religious Visions in American Art," by Ilise S. Carter, 1995 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous Notes and Writings by Others, 1975-1990, undated, (2 folders) (Box 10, Folder 13-14)
  - Oversized Notes on Individual Art Work, undated, (from Box 8, Folder 22) (Box 28)
- Scrapbook, 1965-1976, Series 6:; (Box 10; 1 folder)
  A scrapbook of unbound pages of clippings and newsletters about Hemphill, his collection, and exhibitions of folk art.
  - Scrapbook, 1965-1976 (Box 10, Folder 15)
- Printed Material, 1776-1998, Series 7:; (Box 10-19, 28-29, OV 31; 9.5 linear feet)
  Voluminous printed material includes clippings, announcements and catalogs for exhibitions, auctions and festivals, press releases, calendars of events, travel booklets, brochures, programs, and menus. There are brochures about the sale of art work, galleries, museums, miscellaneous organizations, conferences, schools, lectures, antique and craft shops, films, publications, restaurants, household items, and historical topics. Also found are brochures about miscellaneous artists including Miles Carpenter, S. P. Dinsmoor, Lonnie Holley, Clementine Hunter, and Veronica Terrillion, as well as autographed copies of booklets The Black Swan and Other Poems by James Merrill, and The Blood of Jesus by Thomas Jefferson Flanagan. There are also picture postcards of various sites around the world and miscellaneous art work, in addition to novelty postcards, sheet music, miscellaneous business cards for Hemphill and others, and miscellaneous printed material including a 1776 thirty shilling note from New Jersey.
  - Clippings, undated, (11 folders; Oversized material also housed in Box 28) (Box 10, Folder 16-26)
  - Clippings, 1790 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Clippings, 1800 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Clippings, 1831-1833 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Clippings, 1872 (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - Clippings, 1874 (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Clippings, 1878 (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - Clippings, 1891 (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - Clippings, 1908-1936 (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - Clippings, 1940-1946 (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - Clippings, 1947 (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - Clippings, 1951-1953 (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - Clippings, 1954 (Box 10, Folder 38)
  - Clippings, 1961-1963 (Box 10, Folder 39)
  - Clippings, 1964-1972, (41 folders; Oversized materials also housed in Box 28) (Box 10, Folder 40-80)
  - Clippings, 1983-1998, (58 folders; Oversized materials also housed in Box 28) (Box 11, Folder 1-58)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs for Artists with Surnames "A"-"F," undated (Box 11, Folder 59)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs for Artists with Surnames "G"-"M," undated (Box 11, Folder 60)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs for Artists with Surnames "N"-"R," undated (Box 11, Folder 61)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs for Artists with Surnames "S," undated (Box 11, Folder 62)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs for Artists with Surnames "T," undated (Box 11, Folder 63)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs for Artists with Surnames "U"-"Z," undated, (Oversized material also housed in Box 29) (Box 11, Folder 64)
  - General Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, undated, (8 folders; Oversized material also housed in OV 31) (Box 12, Folder 1-8)
  - General Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, 1948-1949 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - General Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, 1951-1987, (37 folders; Oversized material also housed in OV 31) (Box 12, Folder 10-47)
  - General Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, 1988-1995, (54 folders) (Box 13, Folder 1-54)
  - General Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, 1995-1998, (39 folders; Oversized material also housed in Box 29) (Box 14, Folder 1-39)
  - Auction Announcements and Catalogs, 1988-1997, undated, (3 folders) (Box 14, Folder 40-42)
  - Announcements for Festivals and Miscellaneous Events, 1978-1996, undated, (3 folders) (Box 14, Folder 43-45)
  - Press Releases, 1961-1997, undated, (14 folders) (Box 14, Folder 46-59)
  - Calendars of Events, 1974-1997, (7 folders; Oversized material also housed in Box 29) (Box 14, Folder 60-66)
  - Booklets and Brochures about Artists (Box 15)
    - Joe Barta, undated (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Miles Carpenter; George Carr, 1924, undated, (Oversized material also housed in Box 29) (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - S. Thad Cherry; Hinson C. Cole; Carolyn Sihler Connors, 1989, undated (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Evan Decker, undated (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - S. P. Dinsmoor, 1972, undated (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Lonnie Holley; Clementine Hunter; Virgil Perry, undated (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Veronica Terrillion; Michael Thonet, undated (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Shozo Uchii, 1985 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Travel Booklets and Brochures (Box 15)
    - Austria (Salzburg), undated (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Greece, undated (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Syria, undated (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Turkey, undated (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - United States, undated, (13 folders) (Box 15, Folder 13-25)
    - England, Scotland, and Wales, 1960-1995, undated (Box 15, Folder 26)
    - Japan, Thailand, Burma, and India, 1961-1973, undated, (7 folders; Oversized material also housed in Box 29) (Box 15, Folder 27-33)
    - Canada and for Expo '67, 1967-1985, undated, (3 folders) (Box 15, Folder 34-36)
    - South America, 1969 (Box 15, Folder 37)
    - United States, Bicentennial Roadbook, 1976 (Box 15, Folder 38)
    - Africa, 1988, undated (Box 15, Folder 39)
    - "Hanseatic Passage" (Scandinavia, Russia, Poland, Germany, The Netherlands), 1989, (4 folders) (Box 15, Folder 40-43)
    - France, Portugal, and Spain, 1990, (6 folders) (Box 15, Folder 44-49)
    - United States (Louisiana), 1990 (Box 15, Folder 50)
    - United States (Alaska), 1990-1993, (2 folders) (Box 15, Folder 51-52)
    - Melanesia and Papua New Guinea, 1991-1992 (Box 15, Folder 53)
    - Trans-Siberian Railway, 1994 (Box 15, Folder 54)
    - The Netherlands and Belgium, 1995 (Box 15, Folder 55)
    - France, 1995 (Box 15, Folder 56)
    - American Orient Express, 1996 (Box 15, Folder 57)
    - Mexico, 1996 (Box 15, Folder 58)
    - Booklets and Brochures for the Sale of Art Work, 1951-1995, (4 folders; Oversized materials also housed in Box 29) (Box 15, Folder 59-62)